

NATALIA M. HESS FULL STACK DEVELOPER

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML React CSS Node.js JavaScript Rails jQuery Gulp.js Ruby Bootstrap Python Mocha Liquid lasmine MongoDB RSpec PostgreSQL Git/GitHub AngularJS Sketch

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY
2017 User Experience Design
2016 Full Stack Web Development

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, DAVIS 2010 - 2014 B.A. Political Science & German, Honors

OTHER SKILLS

Lecturing and 1-on-1 teaching
Writing (technical and non-technical)
Speaking at events and panels
Welding and metal sculpting
German and Spanish languages

CONTACT

✓ nataliam.hess@gmail.com

(650) 200-8474

in linkedin.com/in/nataliahess

github.com/nathess91

EXPERIENCE

LEAD WEB DEVELOPER

AQUIS | February 2017 - Present

- Built custom e-commerce storefront (US and UK) using front end technologies (JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML), Ruby, and Gulp.js
- Owned the design and development of blog interface
- Translated Lead Designer's Photoshop comps with precision
- Ensured frictionless, user-centered design with A/B and user tests
- Used agile methodologies to define deadlines and weekly sprints
- Led team meetings to discuss technical pain points and solutions HIGHLIGHTS

25% increase in conversions

58% decrease in bounce rates

Sole developer

Taught myself Liquid (Shopify's RoR-based language) in 1 week

UX/UI DESIGNER & CONSULTANT

Freelance | February 2017 - Present

- Design goal-based web mockups and interfaces for clients
- Collaborate with developers to bring mockups to life
- Drive user research and develop interaction/visual design for product marketing
- Create A/B tests and analyze user behavior with Google Analytics

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT TEACHING ASSISTANT

General Assembly | February 2017 - Present

- Tutored students and assisted with troubleshooting/debugging
- Helped students develop their own processes and strategies for breaking down complex problems

HIGHLIGHTS

Invited to renew contract after positive feedback from students and management

PROJECTS

Paid

Collaborative React-on-Rails app that manages monthly bills and dates

 Built UI components, architected and built back end, managed project team, primary UX designer

Built with HTML, CSS, React, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript

DockIt

Custom CRM designed for a nationally-based restoration company to organize all assignment details from start to finish

Designed and developed everything across the full stack, worked with a client to define product vision

Built with HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GitHub

FellowshipAdvisor

Mimics TripAdvisor with a Tolkien twist

Created original project theme, integrated REST API Built with *HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GitHub*